

Md. Jubaer Khan

GitHub

<u>in</u> <u>LinkedIn</u>

(+8801610132500

CAREER OBJECTIVE

I focus on helping an organization become more effective in accomplishing its business objectives by finding and executing continual improvements and always striving to create high standards in all areas. I have experience developing software, conducting academic research, data science, and developing websites. I'd particularly like to establish my career in a reputable organization where I can demonstrate my educational ability.

Education

BSc (CSE), North South University, Dhaka Bangladesh- May 2017 – May 2021

- CGPA: 3.59/4.0
- Specialization courses: Machine Learning, Theory of Computation, Pattern Recognition and Neural Network, Mobile and Wireless Application Development

Professional Experience

Intern (Office of Information Technology) - Feb 2021 – Jun 2021

- Developed a chatbot
- Design workflow for the project
- Build a dataset for training Machine Learning model
- Design architecture for the chatbot
- Develop backend using some machine learning tools
- Apply and test different frameworks from python for better user experience
- Website deployment for a python application
- Debugging the codes

Student Worker (Office of IT support Team)

North South University - Aug 2018 - Jan 2021

- Provide technical support to faculty members, officials and students
- Prepare PCs for Printing and Engineering Labs (OS, Software Installation, IP and domain setup).
- Provide support for different troubleshooting software, print driver management, and hardware of printing and Computer Labs.
- Maintain an information desk for users, IT service forms and keep track of them.
- Paper Cut Server configuration, troubleshooting and maintenance support.
- Provide technical support in different Programming Contests held by university.
- Assist the IT officials for Classroom and other IT services

Scholarships and Awards

University financial aid - Jan 2020 - May 2021

Skills

- Document Creation: Microsoft Office Suite, LaTex
- Application Development tool: Android studio, Eclipse
- Design tools: CorelDRAW, Figma (Web-based UI/UX design tools)

- Programming Languages: C, C++, Java, Python (NumPy, SciPy, Matplotlib, Pandas, etc.)
- Good knowledge about Git-based code hosting and collaboration tool (GitHub, Bitbucket)
- Basic knowledge of Machine learning and data mining.
- Problem-solving and critical reasoning skills
- Knowledge over HTML, CSS and MySQL
- High attention to detail
- Quick learner

Projects and Research

• Data mining from cord

I am extracting some relational information using some NLP models. Python and some popular data handling tools are using to mining effective information.

Food delivery application design

I designed a Figma-based UI design for the food delivery application.

Menu Whiz

A cross-platform application that helps users to a restaurant's menu and ordering food can be more straightforward. For developing this application HTML, CSS, Django, java, android studio and NFC are used.

• Retinal-Image-Segmentation

The aim of this project is to detect retinal diseases from available retinal datasets(images). A CNN architecture is used to segmenting retinal blood vessels from retinal images. TensorFlow framework is used for this project.

• Office Management System

A simple office management tool is written in the C programming language designed to organize officials, their assigned projects and quickly track work progress.

• Student-teacher communication application

A helping application for study using java in Eclipse. GUI also used to develop this application

• Travel Agency System

A web application to help travelers to choose packages and travel agencies offer packages. HTML, CSS, JavaScript and MySQL are used to create this web application.

References

Mohammad Rashed Mazumder

Network Manager Office of Information Technology North South University

Email: rashed.mazumder@northsouth.edu

Phone: +880-2-55668200 Ext: 1407

Colonel Md. Mahfuzul Haque (Retd.)

Group Head of Safety and Security DBL Group

Email: mahfuzul.haque@dbl-group.com

Phone: +8801708151617